Colin James MacGeorge

265 W McMillan St. Apt. 6 Cincinnati, OH 45219 440.787.5988 colinmacgeorge@gmail.com

Young professional, adjunct professor and multimedia coordinator at a major university pursuing opportunity with a live media production company where academic, professional and creative skills can be embedded in a successful team driven environment.

EXPERIENCE

Adjunct Instructor Aug 2019 - Present

University of Cincinnati, Electronic Media Division

Integrated Media Production class focused on creative media production and industry standard media production technologies. Provide an environment for students to learn to use the tools of digital media for personal and professional projects.

Multimedia Coordinator & Live Streaming Producer

Aug 2018 - Present

University of Cincinnati, College Conservatory of Music Information Technology Division

- Provide Level 2 IT support for faculty, staff and students
- Configure workflows, operate technical equipment and manage team of specialists for live production and streaming of Conservatory of Music performances:
 - o Encoder set-up, signal patching management
 - Establish content distribution network to broadcast live at multiple bitrates
 - Multi-Camera configuration, ATEM switcher, video camera conversion and live captioning integration via ASR and character generation methods
 - o Canopy Video, Echo 360, Universal capture, Pro-Tools 7 Digital Audio
- Produce short instructional technology videos (tutorials) for faculty and staff
- Write and update knowledge-based articles for various software

Videographer and Archival Recording Tech

Feb 2016 - Apr 2018

University of Cincinnati, College Conservatory of Music

- Produced videos for University preparatory and community engagement departments for summer programs and various live University events
- Record live performances (musical, theatrical, webinars) for recoding production department
- Edited and archived performances into digital resource commons.

Videographer/Photo Intern

Jan 2018 - Apr 2019

Cincinnati Symphony Orchestra, Cincinnati, OH

- Contributed to improved website design using basic HTML and Java coding
- Photographed (video/still) and recorded rehearsals and live performances

Multimedia Intern

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

Culture Monster LLC, Cincinnati, OH

• Assisted documentary filmmaker David Donnelly with content creation, production and editing of on-line promotional and marketing videos.

EDUCATION

University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, OH

Aug 2015 - Apr 2018

Bachelor of Fine Arts, Electronic Media & Certificate Broadcast News

Colin James MacGeorge

714 Riddle Road, Unit 102 Cincinnati, OH 45220 440.787.5988 colinmacgeorge@gmail.com

Ludwig-Maximilian University, Munich, Germany

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

 Media summer curriculum and internship w/m94.5 Munich Radio. Operated in the Music Journalism division of radio station. Wrote and produced daily short segments aired live over m94.5FM

CREDITS

Producer

The Music of Stevie Wonder – CCM Jazz Lab Band College Conservatory of Music @ The University of Cincinnati https://ccm.uc.edu/video.html

• Multicamera live stream

The Ariel Quartet – The Fugue College Conservatory of Music @ The University of Cincinnati https://ccm.uc.edu/video.html

Multicamera live stream

UC Philharmonia Season Opening Concert College Conservatory of Music @ The University of Cincinnati https://ccm.uc.edu/video.html

• Multicamera live stream

Sep 20th, 2019

Oct 22nd, 2019

Nov 3rd, 2019

SKILLS

Live multicamera video/audio streaming technical production Video editing/conferencing software (WebEx, Zoom, MS Team) Video Captioning software and workflows (Aegisub, Premiere Pro, Cielo24) Basic HTML and JAVA Coding